# **MAKI HIROSE**

Portfolio: makidesigner.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/makihirose

Contact: maki@makidesigner.com | +81 50 5806 3669 | Kyoto, Japan (remote work)

### **SUMMARY**

Digital Lead with UX/UI design and coding skills.

Bilingual in English and Japanese.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

<u>UX/UI:</u> User Research, Market Research, Contextual Inquiry, User Interviewing, Affinity Mapping, User Persona, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, User Flow, Sketching, Wireframing, Wireflow, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Prototyping, Responsive Web Design, Design Systems, WCAG.

**Web Development:** React, JavaScript, CSS, JSX, HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery, RESTful API, AJAX, AXIOS, JSON, Firebase, Node, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, ORM, Handlebars, Heroku, JawsDB, mLab, Chrome DevTools, Git, GitHub, Agile, Scrum.

**Software:** VS Code, Sketch, Figma, XD, InVision, Photoshop, Lightroom, Bridge, After Effects, Premiere, Audition, Capture One, Photo Mechanic, Final Cut Pro, Logic Pro, Pro Tools, Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Google Slides, AEM, Adobe Analytics, Azure DevOps, Jira, Command Line.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## RR Donnelley - Digital Lead - Tokyo, Japan

2021-Present

Assigned to the Morgan Stanley account, led and managed UX/UI design and web development projects. Transformed the cross functional team from Waterfall to Agile. Led APAC region Morgan Stanley website initiatives, generating over 20000 views in the first five days of a high profile launch.

## KPMG Ignition Tokyo - UX/UI Designer - Tokyo, Japan

2020-2021

Designing UX/UI for Machine Learning, AI, OCR and Blockchain platforms. Member of an award-winning Data Science team that develops cloud based enterprise solutions for KPMG Japan and Australia's Audit, Tax, Advisory and Consulting service lines. Notable accomplishments include creating the first patented Excel Mapping UI and Machine Learning PDF Annotation UI in the world, and the first Design System within the KPMG global network.

## Tanqueray Gin - Product Designer - New York, USA

2016-2020

Redesigned TanquerayGin.com from scratch with the team and implemented incremental updates. Contributed to UX/UI design and led the team through the visual design ideation and execution.

## Maybelline - Product Designer - New York, USA

2015-2016

Developed and launched Maybelline's new Fit Me! web app. Contributed to UX/UI design and mentored the team through the visual design ideation and creation process.

## <u>Smirnoff</u> - <u>Product Designer</u> - New York, USA

2012-2015

Executed Smirnoff.com's multiple redesign processes. Contributed to UX/UI and visual design.

# **MAKI HIROSE**

Page Two of Two

<u>Drive In Studios</u> - Web Designer & Digital Imaging Specialist - New York, USA

2007-2012

Designed and coded company and client sites. Supervised digital imaging and retouching on photoshoots.

• Notable Clients: IBM, GE, Citi, Microsoft, Sony, Vodafone, Merck, AstraZeneca, Allianz and more.

### **EDUCATION**

**New York University** - New York, USA UX Design for Emerging Technologies

<u>Columbia University</u> - New York, USA

Full Stack Web Development

New York University - New York, USA

Bachelors of Fine Art in Photography & Imaging
New York University Honors Scholar and Founders' Day Award Recipient - *Tisch School of the Arts* 

St. Paul's School - London, UK

Japanese School in London (Hoshuko Saturday School) - London, UK

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) - Scrum Alliance - New York, USA

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - Scrum Alliance - New York, USA